<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>BLOG_NAME</title>
 <link href="YOUR_URL/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="YOUR_URL"/>
 <updated>2013-09-18T10:22:54+02:00</updated>
 <id>BLOG_URL</id>
 <author>
   <name>BLOG_NAME</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Mack, teacher at the ouagon</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/mack-prof-au-wagon.html"/>
   <updated>2013-09-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/mack-prof-au-wagon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-fluid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;span4 center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mack.png&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;span8&quot;style=&quot;padding-left:10px;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Ancien élève du &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.devbootcamp.com/&quot;&gt;Devbootcamp&lt;/a&gt;, Mack vit en France depuis 1 an. Après avoir travaillé chez &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tigerlilyapps.com/fr/&quot;&gt;Tiger Lily&lt;/a&gt;, il a décidé de se concentrer sur son site de vente de whiskey &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tastersclub.com/&quot;&gt;Taster's club&lt;/a&gt; et de rejoindre l'équipe du wagon pour enseigner **le code qui sert**. Il nous parle de son expérience à DBC et de son rôle au wagon, forgive the english !&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;red&quot;&gt;Likes&lt;/span&gt;: The Beatles, Yerba Maté, Star Wars, #A3DAFF &amp; #FCE092, Yeezus&lt;p/&gt;
        &lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;red&quot;&gt;Dislikes&lt;/span&gt;: soda, hunting, Dawson's Creek, liars&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;What did you learn during DBC that helped you find a job?&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;What was great about Dev Bootcamp is that they not only taught the fundamentals of Ruby/Rails (the essentials to getting a Rails gig), but the more intangible parts of what it means to be a good developer - taking and giving feedback on your work, how to be that guy people want to work with, how to bring a fresh perspective to a project. They taught me that being a good developer means a lot more than writing good code - there's such a human element to the whole thing that people sometimes ignore. I still have a lot of work to do on both sides of that equation, but I'm really thankful that they encouraged me to have that holistic perspective.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;What did you do after the DBC?&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;I moved to Paris the better part of a year ago. For most of that time, I was working for a startup as a rails developer at Tigerlily but more recently started focusing full-time on Taster's Club, a whiskey &quot;learning/drinking club&quot; that I've been running out of the US for the last year. Coming soon to France...&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;What do you do know? Do you use what you learn at DBC on a daily basis?&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Yes, I use this stuff all the time. If you have a business online that you want to optimize, it can require a good deal of maintenance, especially in the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;When I started TC I had a spreadsheet that I would use to manage customers. Everything administrative would happen in excel - recording how many bottles everyone received, cancellations, renewals, upgrade, shipping history, etc… It got pretty unwieldy as my membership grew - I knew it wasn't the best solution.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;Now we have an web app to handle all the administration of our members' subscriptions, generate email communication to members, receipts, create and send out our PDF welcome certificate, etc… We use Stripe to process our subscription payments. Our blog is powered by Jekyll. It's all sitting on Heroku. It's much easier and takes way less time. It was obvious that something like this is the best solution but it wasn't until I learned to code that I could actually make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;What will be your role for le wagon's 1st class program? What do you want to teach students?&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;I want to encourage the students to have a goal in mind when they are learning to code. 

When I learned to code, the moments where I was learning just for the sake of learning weren't always super productive. On the other hand, when I could relate what I was learning to something I was trying to build, every lesson meant so much more. I was more curious, too - I couldn't stop asking questions. If a student can get fired up about making something in particular, they're going to learn to get there faster and with a purpose.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Pierre Kosciusko-Morizet répond au wagon</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/pkm-repond-au-wagon.html"/>
   <updated>2013-09-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/pkm-repond-au-wagon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row-fluid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;span4 center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pkm.jpg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;span8&quot;style=&quot;padding-left:10px;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Pierre Kosciusko-Morizet est CEO de &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.priceminister.com/&quot;&gt;PriceMinister&lt;/a&gt; et co-fondateur du fonds d'investissement &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isai.fr/&quot;&gt;ISAI&lt;/a&gt;. Il s'est prêté au jeu d'une petite interview pour le Wagon...&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;br/&gt;
        &lt;h4 class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;Qu'attendez vous d'une nouvelle recrue?&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Le plus important dans le web c’est l’envie d’apprendre : tout bouge trop vite, donc les connaissances ne sont valables que peu de temps, il faut aimer le changement...&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;br/&gt;
        &lt;h4 class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;Plus spécifiquement sur des postes techniques?&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;En plus de l’envie de se former en permanence, je dirais la capacité à travailler en équipe, et aussi la motivation, l’envie de réaliser les choses bien.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;Comment ça marche, en ce moment, le recrutement de développeurs?&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Chez PriceMinister, on a la chance d’avoir beaucoup de candidatures spontanées, donc on arrive à avoir une très très bonne équipe. Mais je vois beaucoup de startups qui démarrent ayant du mal à recruter : on manque cruellement de développeurs en France...&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;Quelle est la place des développeurs dans vos équipes? leur quotidien?&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Il s’agit de l’équipe la plus importante en taille. De plus, toute la société tourne autour de la technique : la plupart des équipes ont besoin d’évolutions techniques pour mettre en musique leurs idées. Donc la technique est forcément très centrale. C’est indispensable dans une boite web !!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;Back in the day, auriez-vous suivi un programme comme 1ère classe? pour quelles raisons?&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Même si je comprends les bases de l’IT en général, j’aurais bien aimé mieux comprendre ce qu’est «développer», donc pourquoi pas !  En tout cas, longue vie à l’initiative 1ère classe et bonne chance aux développeurs qui en profiteront !&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wisembly soutient le wagon</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/wisembly-soutient-le-wagon.html"/>
   <updated>2013-09-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/wisembly-soutient-le-wagon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/romain_wisembly.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;romain de wisembly&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;bitter&quot;&gt;Qui es-tu ?&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Je suis co-fondateur de &lt;a href=&quot;http://wisembly.com/fr/&quot;&gt;Wisembly&lt;/a&gt;. Wisembly est une solution collaborative pour les réunions d'entreprise. Notre logicel en SaaS permet de préparer, d'animer et d'assurer le suivi de réunions (séminaires, conférences, conf-call, formation...).
Wisembly a été fondée en 2010. Nous avons aujourd'hui près de 300 clients et 17 employés.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pull-right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/wisembly.png&quot; alt=&quot;wisembly&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;Quels profils recherchez-vous chez Wisembly ?&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Nous recherchons à la fois des profils commerciaux et des profils plus techniques. 
Dans notre équipe technique, nous voulons des gens motivés, très compétents dans leur domaine, capables de travailler en équipe et maîtrisant toutes les bonnes pratiques de développement.
Côté produit, nous cherchons des profils capables de comprendre les tenants et les aboutissants techniques du produit, mais aussi de discuter avec les développeurs, toujours avec une bonne vision utilisateurs bien sûr. Etant donné la taille de l'équipe aujourd'hui, nous privilégions un product designer ayant des compétences en programmation, et capable d'intégrer ses idées, plutôt que d'avoir à engager à la fois un graphiste et un intégrateur.  
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;Avez-vous déjà dû refuser des candidats qui n'étaient pas assez calés en programmation ?&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Oui, ça nous est déjà arrivé pour des postes produit. Il s'agissait de bons profils pourtant, sortant parfois de grandes écoles. Nous rencontrons souvent des candidats avec un bon background produit mais qui ne sont pas capables de comprendre le code ou d'intégrer des features et prototyper rapidement. Il est fondamental dans notre démarche de développement produit au côté de nos clients de pouvoir leur apporter des idées nouvelles et concrètes régulièrement. Pour pouvoir implémenter de nouvelles fonctionnalités rapidement, il faut clairement un bagage en programmation.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;bold&quot;&gt;Pourquoi soutiens-tu le wagon ?&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Le programme &quot;1ère classe&quot; permet d'ouvrir les portes des startup à des profils très intéressants, auxquels il manque simplement un bagage technique. Je pense notamment à un graphiste ou un product manager qui voudrait rejoindre une startup. Pour ce type de profil, les bases techniques et les bonnes pratiques enseignées par le Wagon me semblent essentielles.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>10 questions for modern CEOs</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/10-questions-for-CEOs.html"/>
   <updated>2013-05-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/10-questions-for-CEOs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/test.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;code au camping&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Last May, Le wagon introduced CEOs from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lecamping.org/&quot;&gt;le camping&lt;/a&gt;, Season4 to the basics of design, front-end &amp;amp; back-end development. The idea behing these courses was to give them a basic overview on the essentials: how a website works, responds to requests, treats and stores data, builds and stylizes responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conclusion was what we had predicted. With enough will and analytical background, any beginner can learn to code. Additionally, any entrepreneur worth his salt should at least grasp some web concepts before taking the plunge. Here are a few questions an entrepreneur should ask himself, before starting the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will I be able to handle (at least a little) design by myself, or will I rely entirely on my CTO?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would I design a logo, badges, backgrounds, patterns for my app without losing too much time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What tools and resources do I know to achieve this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I know enough HTML/CSS/Javascript to assist my CTO? Make mockups and maintain a blog?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I know enough Javascript/jQuery to handle simple animation by myself?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would I understand my CTO's day-to-day enough to relate?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would I organise and control the development cycles in my startup?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would I track the necessary analytics for my app? Which information do I need and which tools will most effectively achieve my goals?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I quickly access social data using social APIs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or automate the collection of social data relevant for my business decisions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;These are the necessary questions for the CEO 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;red bold&quot;&gt;Are you on the right track?&lt;/h4&gt;



</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>